# **Scott Thompson**

Ambitious Technology Professional BSc Hons Computing

scottthompsonc107@live.co.uk

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>Portfolio</u>

#### **ABOUT ME**

I am an ambitious technology professional with three years experience and a background in ITIL processes. When at work I am a process driven individual who aims to create clarity from ambiguity and I have a demonstrated track record of success in doing so.

After becoming ITIL 4 Foundation certified I have taken ownership and responsibility over implementing ITIL processes and toolsets for a global SaaS platform.

Although my strength is ITIL processes, my background includes a healthy mixture of technical and analytical work.

#### **CORE SKILLS**

- Excellent organisation skills.
- Ability to communicate and influence effectively.
- Comfortable interacting with stakeholders at all levels of a business.
- Understanding of SLAs/KPIs and ability to deliver results under operational pressures.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- SQL/SSMS
- Atlassian Suite (Jira/JSM/JQL, Confluence, Opsgenie)
- Microsoft Azure
- Windows VMs
- PowerShell
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript/JQuery/PHP
- Web APIs
- GIT Source Control Github/Bitbucket

#### PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATIONS

• ITIL 4 Foundation

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Glasgow Caledonian University** Computing (BSc Hons), 2:1

- Understanding of agile/waterfall methodologies.
- Experience on a development project using scrum methodology - weekly sprints and testdriven development.
- Experience using a **Python** SVM to examine binary classified datasets and make predictions.
- Development of an "Earthquake Tracker" app for Android using British Geological Society Data.
- Experience deploying small single purpose web worker applications in C# to the Azure cloud (e.g. mp3 sampling tool, image thumbnail maker)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **IT Service Manager**

Retail Insight, May 2021 - Present

- Led the design, implementation and maintenance of **Jira Service Desk** system used by operations team.
  - Collaboration across all operations teams and senior stakeholders to gather requirements.
  - Designed a solution with ITIL Principles and the needs of the business in mind
  - **Ownership of rollout** for the new system as the main point of contact.
  - Delivered high quality **insight/reporting** on **Change/Incident/Problem Management**, areas the business did not previously have visibility on.
  - Demonstrated the ability to draw conclusions with JQL by leveraging it to reduce unnecessary callouts for the engineering team, thus avoiding expense for the business.
  - Implementation of **SLA Tracking** in line with established service requirements.
  - Proven ability to **communicate** and **influence** effectively, demonstrated by high quality training materials and blog content.
  - **Research/Testing** to ensure that this solution will suitably onboard clients.
- Ownership of Jira Administration responsibilities.
  - Responsible for Jira **issue/workflow/field configuration** schemes shared by over fifty company managed projects across the global team.
  - Creation of **company managed projects**, as and when required.
  - Managing **user groups** and assigning **user licences** as appropriate.
  - Training colleagues across the business on **JQL** and advocating creation of **dashboards**, enabling them to extract meaningful value from any project.
- Demonstration of excellent interpersonal/communication skills:
  - Prompt and tactful response to colleagues every day, ensuring that all work is carried out efficiently and according to the correct priority.
  - Onboarding of new team members and knowledge transfer.
- Advocating for a shift-left approach to the operational support model.
  - **Empowering** first and second line teams to reduce non-essential escalation by ensuring that a suitable **knowledge base** is in place.
  - Identifying missing information in the support playbook before creating or seeking content to fill these gaps.
- Responsible for gathering and documenting existing SLAs.
- Ownership of monthly service review for operations teams.
  - Ensuring progress on tickets raised and fostering accountability.
  - Identification of blockers by seeking clarity on tickets that have not moved.
- Creation of high quality documentation on **Atlassian Confluence**:
  - **Overhaul** of outdated or ambiguous documentation.
  - **Creation** of new documentation in places where none existed previously.
  - Ensuring **clarity** not only on what should be done, but also why.
  - Introduced documentation practice for standard changes, allowing their implementation to be pre-approved by management and removing this barrier where it is not strictly required.
- Project work to replace legacy alerting/reporting procedures using Atlassian
  OpsGenie:
  - Review of existing alerting process.
  - Migrating alerts from old configurations slack/email for example.
  - Evaluation appropriate alerting thresholds.

#### **FURTHER EXPERIENCE**

# **Application Support Engineer**

Retail Insight, Jan 2020 - May 2021

- Working closely with **agile** teams across the business and around the globe.
  - Attending **daily standups** with Development teams.
  - Contributing to **sprint planning**, ensuring that release schedules are realistic while still meeting operational pressures.
  - Working closely with Development team members to assist with identification of bugs.
  - Collaboration with Data Administration team to **investigate** and **rectify** discrepancies in sales/store data.
- Maintenance of environments (test, acceptance, production):
  - Deployment of release candidate code in line with relevant process.
  - Responsible for restores across environments as required.
- **Responding to alerts** to prevent issues on a global **SaaS** platform:
  - **Incident response and issue diagnosis**, escalating where appropriate Initial triage of issues and correct categorisation of the severity of the incident.
  - **Demonstrated sense of urgency** to prevent major incidents.
  - Prompt communication of incidents and their severity to relevant stakeholders.
  - Collaboration to establish a **communication plan** for the affected customers when appropriate.
  - Working with SLAs in mind to ensure that any unavoidable business impact is limited.
- **24/7 incident response** one week in four, as per on-call rota.
- Automation of repetitive tasks using Powershell, SQL Agent jobs and Tocabot (Automated Windows)
  - Design and implementation of solutions for receiving data from Web APIs
  - Installation and monitoring of housekeeping jobs to ensure disk space remains at acceptable capacity on all systems.
- Implementation of dashboards (holistics/redash) to monitor Data Accuracy.
  - Designing and implementing a solution that does not impose non-essential risk to service.
  - Delivering insight on data to business facing colleagues without exposing any resources unnecessarily. Colleagues can access dashboard information on demand, but cannot carry out operations on the system(s).

# **Sales Assistant (Various Departments)**

John Lewis Partnership, July 2018 – Jan 2020

- Building rapport with customers and colleagues.
- Responding to customer queries and helping customers to find the right product.
- Efficient and polite customer service while responding to any feedback to ensure customer satisfaction with every customer, every time.

#### **Loss Prevention Receptionist**

John Lewis Partnership, July 2017 - July 2018

- Following all procedures for managing both visitor and partner access.
- Call handling for Store Reception and Loss Prevention department.
- Working with loss prevention partners to ensure the protection of partners, customers and business assets.
- Use of CCTV and incident database systems to investigate issues and record incidents.
- Use of EPOS sales database to investigate sales discrepancies.

# Summer Intern - IT Networking & Comms

Argyll & Bute Council, Summer 2016

- Supporting end users of the council's network and communicating solutions to problems.
- Day-to-day network monitoring and intrusion detection.
- Working on site with colleagues to install networking equipment.

This role provided me with a variety of networking experience including:

- Hands on experience with configuration & installation of cisco networking hardware.
- Experience configuring IP reservations for a wide area network.
- Use of RDP for troubleshooting or network configuration from a remote location